Contact

9514968820 (Mobile) nicolemibarra@icloud.com

www.linkedin.com/in/nicole-ibarra-b002b3b0 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Customer Service Inventory Management Team Building

Nicole Ibarra

Customer Logistics Manager at Ryder Supply Chain Solutions Fontana, California

Summary

Pursuing a Master of Science Degree in Leadership and Management with a Human Resource concentration from the University of La Verne's School of Business. Also possess fifteen years of experience managing hundredths of union and non-union employees from an array of socioeconomic, cultural, work experience and education backgrounds in Southern California. Strategically focused on achieving sustainable results. Excel in using information technology to improve operating efficiencies. Work well in cooperation with others to accomplish organizational goals. Recognize the importance of quality in providing a competitive edge.

Experience

Ryder Supply Chain Solutions Customer Logistics Manager August 2017 - Present

Fontana, California

- Responsible for the leadership of direct reports as well as the attainment of daily operational goals and objectives within Inventory Control.
- Advanced level skills in MS Excel such as keyboard short cuts, creating macros, merge, merge queries, templates, table techniques, and working with images and text.
- Experience with ground transportation operations including DOT, OSHA and all related safety regulations.
- Knowledge/Experience in transportation environment (i.e., Shipping, receiving and inventory management, distribution or dispatch).
- Knowledge of warehouse and or software applications, routing and dispatch software systems.
- Excellent written, verbal and organizational skills.
- Attainment of productivity goals resolving customer issues.
- Quality Assurance Safety Management and reporting New Employee training.

- Works in a dynamic environment focusing on delivery of continuous measurable improvement to the customer.
- Ensure Inventory Control meets all productivity goals and objectives while achieving employee relations solutions.

Vans a Division of VF Outdoor Processing Supervisor March 2015 - August 2017 (2 years 6 months)

Santa Fe Springs, California

- Ensure fiscal responsibility targets are met including; budgets and forecasts, cost control and reporting as it relates to labor planning and supplies.
- Assume responsibility of product from replenishment on a wave by wave basis through fast pick/shelf picking, trouble resolution and VAS.
- Ensure staffing levels are appropriate for all aspects of the daily/monthly workflow.
- Set clear and measurable goals for all associates on a daily/monthly/yearly basis.
- Provide supervisory leadership to area associates to ensure outstanding service to internal and external customers
- Establish workload priorities and provides clear daily objectives for the area under supervision.
- Create, generates and analyzes DC/LM reports to ensure throughput goals are being met.
- Ensure full compliance with VF policies and procedures.
- Ensure the DC is 'tour ready' at all times.

Pier 1 Imports

DC Supervisor

November 2013 - March 2015 (1 year 5 months)

Ontario, California

- Supported the implementation of best practices while being customer service oriented.
- Analyzed information and used appropriate judgment to execute agreed upon strategies.
- Built collaborative relationships with all levels of management.

- Lead teams to achieve goals and objectives while managing the financial performance of assigned departments within the DC, to include monitoring appropriate staffing levels, reducing damages and controlling supply costs.
- Lead and supported an effective Safety program.
- Provided verbal and written recognition and feedback to associates through daily communication and biannual reviews.
- Engaged teams to ensure a high level of associate involvement by continual mentoring and motivating.
- Ensured all policies and procedures are adhered to and effectively managed.

The Home Depot

Area Supervisor

March 2012 - November 2013 (1 year 9 months)

Redlands, California

- Managed processes by ensuring all operation procedures were followed effectively, and identify and recommend needed changes.
- Trained, coached and developed associates in daily operations to ensure a high degree of safety, quality and performance through factual data and subjective observations.
- Drove results by reviewing reports to identifying areas of improvement for key metrics including productivity, accuracy, quality, and expenses.
- Business planned through coordinating and monitoring operations to ensure performance production rates were consistent with business plan and pattern, reducing irregularities and damages.
- Lead an hourly team and influence the entire distribution team to do the fastpaced work required to run the distribution center as efficiently, safely and productively as possible.
- Responsible for ensuring prompt, efficient and accurate handling of merchandise as well as developing and implementing team goals.

UPS

Supervisor

April 2003 - March 2012 (9 years)

Ontario, California

- Executed plan and coordinated inbound and outbound package process flow to ensure appropriate employee scheduling and proper loading for timely departure.
- Reviewed previous day's reports (e.g., time and labor, data on pieces per hour, etc.) to determine acceptable levels of performance and make changes to current operations.

- Ensured customer service elements were attained by conducting daily audits and fostering employee accountability.
- Provided quality communication to subordinates, coworkers, and superiors through multiple forms of daily announcements, meetings, written documentation, phone conversations, and performance evaluations.
- Identified potential or existing operational process issues and resolved them either personally, through delegation, or involving specified individuals or departments.
- Organized and maintained accurate and updated compliance, forms, reports, and employee profiles.
- Administered effective training to developed and mentored employees to ascertain organizational and personal goals.

Education

University of La Verne

Master of Science (M.S.), Leadership and Management · (2018)

Rio Hondo College

Associate of Arts (A.A.), Liberal Studies

University of La Verne

Bachelor of Science (B.S.), Organizational Leadership